Divide and conquer algorithm.
A divide and conquer algorithm is a strategy of solving a larger problem by breaking the problem into
smaller sub problems, solving the sub problems and combining them to get the desired outcome.
Like this division and conquering, so we have divided the array into two subcategories, some erase
and we have sorted that.
We have divided them also into sub arrays.
We have arranged them.
Order them and sorted them.
And then we combined the whole arrays into a sorted.
Saturday.
To use that divide and conquer algorithm, rigour, recursion is used.
Please go back to the previous sections in order to to learn about that occurred again and in order
to continue with the next algorithms and to be familiar what we are used, why we are using recursion
and how to use their recursion again mechanics.
Here are the steps divide, divide that given problem into sub problems using recursion.
Conquer solved the smaller sub problems recursively, if the sub problem is small enough, then solve
it directly.
Combined combine is the solution combined the solutions of the sub problems that are part of the recursive
process to solve the actual problem.
So divide and conquer versus the dynamic algorithms.
This is the divide and conquer approach.
This is the Fibonacci that we have sold it in.
The previous bit is in the recursion, so please go back to the recursion.
If you want to learn more about this Fibonacci solving, Fibonacci and recursion.
So if and less than to then return one and else return Fibonacci of and minus one, plus Fibonacci of
and minus dos, this is you solved by referring and using the recursion.
We have divided into subcategories and we have concurred.
The approach, dynamic approach.
We create them equal to Iran and Fibonacci, and if and in MIM, then return memory.
And often, if any less than to equal to one else, equal to us and minus one plus and minus two.
And if an equal f and then return, this is that dynamic approach we have learned.
Also, this approach is in solving Fibonacci, not in recursion.
OK.
So.
Divide and conquer advantages, the complexity of them for the multiplication of two matrices is using
their naive method is oh, two two and power three.
Whereas using the divide and conquer approach such that stressing matrix multiplication is all to end
to power.
Two point eight It is less than two power three and the Q.
So this approach also simplifies other problems such as Tower of Hanoi, and we will learn later on
in the next videos about the Tower of another.
And this threatens matrix multiplication.
This approach is suitable for multiple processing systems.
It makes efficient use of memory code catches and the divide and conquer applications.
It's found in the binary search that we are going to learn in the previous video in their next videos.
Also, the Merge sort that we are going to start with it in their next video and their quick sort.
Later on and the stress matrix multiplication and that got a toolbar algorithm.
So these are the application of the divide and concur application.
Let's move to the Merge sort algorithm animation and learn about the Merge sort and that how to implement
and use, divide and conquer.